Guide to the Western Film Lobby Card and Poster Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Western film lobby card and poster collection
1916-1980
WA MSS S-2607
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3.87
(9 boxes) + 7 rolls, 6 broadside folders
The collection consists primarily of lobby cards, posters, and promotional fliers, relating to western films made from 1916 to the 1980s. There are also some pressbooks and photographs in the collection. Represented within the collection are works by notable directors, such as John Ford, Howard Hawks, Allan Dwan, Henry King, Billy Wilder, Roman Polanski, William S. Hart, Sergio Leone, André de Toth, Nicholas Ray, Raoul Walsh, Anthony Mann, and Sam Peckinpah. Also represented are works featuring notable western stars, such as William S. Hart, William Boyd as Hopalong Cassidy, Gene Autry, Roy Rogers, Buck Jones, and Harry Carey, among others. Highlights include original posters for Stagecoach (1939), directed by John Ford, and the original poster for the Italian release of Per qualche dollaro in più (For a Few Dollars More) (1965).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was purchased from WalterFilm.com on the Arthur Corbitt Hoskins Memorial Fund in 2007. Additional material acquired through gift and purchase from Walter Reuben, 2011-2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of primarily of lobby cards, posters, and promotional fliers, relating to western films made from 1916 to the 1980s. There are also some pressbooks and photographs in the collection. Represented within the collection are works by notable directors, such as John Ford, Howard Hawks, Allan Dwan, Henry King, Billy Wilder, Roman Polanski, William S. Hart, Sergio Leone, André de Toth, Nicholas Ray, Raoul Walsh, Anthony Mann, and Sam Peckinpah. Also represented are works featuring notable western stars, such as William S. Hart, William Boyd as Hopalong Cassidy, Gene Autry, Roy Rogers, Buck Jones, and Harry Carey, among others. Highlights include original posters for Stagecoach (1939), directed by John Ford, and the original poster for the Italian release of Per qualche dollaro in più (For a Few Dollars More) (1965).
Arrangement
Material is arranged alphabetically by film title. Larger oversize and rolled items have been physically organized at the end. They are listed alphabetically with a note about their physical location and at the end where they are physically located.
Per qualche dollaro in più (Motion picture); Stagecoach (Motion picture: 1939); Film posters, American; Motion picture actors and actresses -- Posters; Motion picture programs; Western films -- Posters; Fliers; Lobby cards; Photographs; Posters; Autry, Gene, 1907-1998; Boyd, William, 1895-1972; Carey, Harry, 1878-1947; De Toth, André, 1912-2002; Dwan, Allan, 1885-1981; Ford, John, 1894-1973; Hart, William S. (William Surrey), 1864-1946; Hawks, Howard, 1896-1977; Jones, Buck, 1889-1942; King, Henry, 1886-1982; Leone, Sergio, 1929-1989; Mann, Anthony, 1906-1967; Peckinpah, Sam, 1925-1984; Polanski, Roman, 1933-; Ray, Nicholas, 1911-1979; Rogers, Roy, 1911-1998; Walsh, Raoul, 1887-1980; Wilder, Billy, 1906-2002
- 3 Godfathers, poster, 1948 (Box 1)
  General note
  John Ford classic western.
- 7 Hommes Restent a Tuer (Seven Men From Now), French pressbook, 4to, 4 pp., 1956 (Box 1)
  Randolph Scott in a Budd Boetticher western.
- Ace in the Hole, lobby cards (set of 8), 1951 (Box 1)
  Billy Wilder's truculent film, about a vicious newspaper reporter, exiled for his previous bad behavior, to a miserable southwestern town, who takes advantage of a mining accident, with eventual tragic results. One of the classics of 50's film noir.
- Ace in the Hole, lobby card (11" x 14"), 1951 (Box 20 (Oversize))
- Across the Wide Missouri, lobby cards, 1951 (Box 1)
  William Wellman epic with Clark Gable.
- Affair in Reno, title lobby card, 1957 (Box 1)
- Alias Jesse James, lobby card, 1959 (Box 1)
  Bob Hope spoof western.
- Annie Oakley, costume sketch by Walter Plunkett (15" x 19"), 1935 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  Scope and Contents
  Sketch for one of Annie Oakley's outfits from this George Stevens film.
- Apache Rose, lobby cards, 1947 (Box 1)
  Roy Rogers western.
- Arizona Bound, lobby cards, 1927 (Box 1)
  Very early Gary Cooper silent western.
- The Arizona Raiders, lobby card (14" x 8"), 1935 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  Buster Crabbe film, directed by James P. Hogan.
- The Bad Man, photographs (8" x 10"), all double weight, date-stamped, and with studio text on back, 1940 (Box 1)
  One of Ronald Reagan's early appearances in a western. It is frequently speculated that he articulated in his presidency ideas that he picked up from roles that he played onscreen.
- The Bad Man, lobby card, 1941 (Box 1)
- Ballad of Cable Hogue, poster, 1970 (Box 1)
  Sam Peckinpah film, an unusually gentle one.
- Belle of the Yukon, lobby card, 1944 (Box 1)
- Bells of Capistrano, lobby card, 1942 (Box 1)
  Gene Autry western.
- Bells of San Angelo, lobby card, 1947 (Box 1)
- Big Calibre, lobby cards, 1935 (Box 1)
  Bob Steele western.
- The Big Country, lobby card, 1958 (Box 1)
  Directed by William Wyler.
- Billy the Kid, photograph (8" x 10") with printed note on verso, 1930 (Box 1)
  Directed by King Vidor. In this version of the Billy the Kid legend, Billy, after shooting down land baron William Donovan's henchmen for killing Billy's boss, is hunted down and captured by his friend, Sheriff Pat Garrett. He escapes and is on his way to Mexico when Garrett, recapturing him, must decide whether to bring him in or to let him go. This was only director King Vidor's second talking film, and histories of the western cite it as one of the really important early talkies in the genre.
- Black Aces, lobby cards, 1937 (Box 1)
  Buck Jones western.
- Black Rodeo, lobby cards (11" x 14", set of 8), 1972 (Box 20 (Oversize))
- Blazing Frontier, lobby card, 1943 (Box 1)
  Buster Crabbe PRC western.
- Blazing Overland Trail, poster for Chapter One of a western serial, 1956 (Box 1)
- Border Cafe, lobby cards, 1937 (Box 1)
  "Easterner Keith Whitney, son of a wealthy Senator, heads west where he ends up a drunk at a border cafe. After losing the money his father sent him to buy a ranch he learns his father is arriving. Rancher Tex now takes him in and tells his father he is part owner. When his father and girlfriend are kidnaped, Tex and a now reformed Keith take out after them." (www.imdb.com) Harry Carey western.
- Border Incident, poster, 1949 (Box 13 (Broadside))
  Anthony Mann film noir about the smuggling into California of illegal aliens. Mann started his directing career with films noir, and then followed up with ten years of classic westerns, mostly with James Stewart, and this was a sort of transition film between the two genres.
- The Border Patrolman, lobby card, 1936 (Box 1)
  George O'Brien western.
- Border Phantom, lobby cards, 1937 (Box 1)
  Bob Steele Republic B-western.
- The Boy and the Laughing Dog, lobby card, 1959 (Box 1)
- The Brand of Hate, lobby card, 1934 (Box 1)
- Bring Me the Head of Alfredo Garcia, poster, 1974 (Box 1)
  Sam Peckinpah's mad bloodbath of a film.
- Buckskin Lady, poster, 1957 (Box 1)
- Bus Stop, color stills (8" x 10", set of 8), 1956 (Box 19)
  Marilyn Monroe film, directed by Joshua Logan.
- California, pressbook (12" x 15"), 1947 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  Barbara Stanwyck film, directed by John Farrow.
- Call of the Klondike, lobby cards (11" x 14", set of 7), 1926 (Box 20 (Oversize))
- Canadian Mounties vs. Atomic Invaders, lobby card, 1953 (Box 1)
- Canyon of the Fools, lobby card, 1923 (Box 1)
  Very rare silent western starring Harry Carey, who, as an older man, was an important member of John Ford's stock ensemble.
- La Caravane des Hommes Traqués, French pressbook, 4to, 4 pp. (Box 1)
- Carson City, poster, 1952 (Box 1)
  Randolph Scott film directed by Andre deToth.
- Cassidy of Bar 20, lobby card, 1938 (Box 1)
  From the popular Hopalong Cassidy series.
- Cat Ballou, lobby card, 1965 (Box 1)
  Classic western comedy, and this is the iconic lobby card of drunken Lee Marvin on horseback.
- Cattle Drive, poster, 1951 (Box 1)
- Chinatown, lobby card, 1974 (Box 1)
  The iconic card of Jake Gittes (Jack Nicholson) surveying a questionable drought through binoculars. From screenplay by Robert Towne.
- Citizen Kane, glass slide (3.25" x 4.5"), 1940 (Box 22)
  Rare slide, used to promote the film in small theatres at the time of its original release. Contains artwork montage of scenes from the film, including one of the young Kane with his sled "Rosebud" at the bottom left.
- [Citizen Kane] RKO Yearbook 1940-1941 (Box 21 (Oversize))
  Promotional yearbook, which contains a full page devoted to Citizen Kane under its early working title "John Citizen, U.S.A."
- Code of the Range, lobby card, 1936 (Box 1)
  Charles Starrett B-western.
- Come on Cowboy, poster, 1948 (Box 1)
  Mantan Moreland starred in this independent all Black cast western.
- Copper Sky, poster, 1957 (Box 1)
- Cornered, lobby cards, 1932 (Box 1)
  Very early Tim McCoy talking western.
- The Cowboy and the Indians, lobby card, 1949 (Box 1)
- The Cowboy and the Lady, promotional flyer, 4to, 4 pp., 1938 (Box 1)
  Samuel Goldwyn produced from a story by Leo McCarey, western romance with Gary Cooper.
- Curtain Call at Cactus Creek, title lobby card, 1950 (Box 1)
- Dallas, photograph (8" x 10"), 1950 (Box 1)
  Gary Cooper western set in Texas after end of Civil War.
- The Dawn Maker, lobby card, 1916 (Box 1)
  This is an important piece---for a western film both starring and directed by the legendary William S. Hart, an unusual and, sadly, apparently lost film, in which he plays a person half white and half native American. This was a remarkable early effort in silent cinema to portray native people with some depth.
- The Day of the Locust, one sheet poster, 1975 (Box 14 (Broadside))
  John Schlesinger's adaptation of Nathaniel West's apocalyptic novel about 30's Hollywood (Yale has a script for this film).
- Days of Jesse James, lobby card, 1939 (Box 1)
  Early Roy Rogers western for Republic.
- Desperadoes of the West, lobby cards, 1950 (Box 1)
- Devil's Canyon, lobby card, 1953 (Box 1)
  This card is one of a handful of westerns produced during the short-lived "3-D" craze of 1953-1954, and it has border artwork reflecting the three-dimensional gimmick.
- Dirty Harry, photographic stills (8" x 10", set of 20), 1971 (Box 19)
  Clint Eastwood film, directed by Don Siegel.
- Dodge City, lobby card, 1939 (Box 1)
- La Doigt sur la Gachette (Box 1)
- Don Dare-Devil, lobby card, 1925 (Box 1)
  Jack Hoxie silent western.
- Don Daredevil Rides Again, lobby cards, 1951 (Box 1)
  Republic serial.
- Don Q, Son of Zorro, lobby card (11" x 14"), 1925 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  Sequel to Douglas Fairbank's The Mark of Zorro (1920).
- Down Dakota Way, lobby cards, 1949 (Box 1)
- The Drifter, lobby card, 1943 (Box 1)
- Duchess of Idaho, lobby card, 1950 (Box 1)
  MGM western musical.
- East of Eden, photographs (8" x 10", set of 19), 1954 (Box 19)
  James Dean film, directed by Elia Kazan.
- The Enforcer, lobby cards (11" x 14", set of 8), 1976 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  Third Dirty Harry film, staring Clint Eastwood.
- Eyes of Texas, lobby card, 1948 (Box 1)
- The Far Frontier, lobby cards, 1948 (Box 1)
- Feud of the Range, lobby card, 1939 (Box 1)
  Bob Steele film for Metropolitan Pictures.
- Fighting Wildcat, poster, 1957 (Box 1)
- Five Bad Men, lobby cards, 1935 (Box 1)
  Western with Noah Beery, Jr.
- Fort Dobbs, lobby card, 1958 (Box 1)
- Frontier Scout, lobby card, 1938 (Box 1)
  George Houston as Wild Bill Hickok in this Grand National release.
- La Furieuse Chevausee (Tall Man Riding), French pressbook, 4to, 4 pp. (Box 1)
  Randolph Scott western.
- Gambler and the lady, poster, 1952 (Box 2)
- The Gay Desperado, lobby card, 1936 (Box 2)
- The Ghost of Zorro, lobby cards, 1949 (Box 2)
- Ghost Town, lobby cards, 1936 (Box 2)
  Harry Carey western.
- Ghost Town, poster, 1956 (Box 2)
- Giant, photograph (8" x 10"), 1956 (Box 2)
  James Dean and Elizabeth Taylor in this critical George Stevens film about early Twentieth Century Texas
- The Grapes of Wrath, lobby card (14" x 8"), 1940 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  Film directed by John Ford, and based on John Steinbeck's Pulitzer Prize-winning novel of the same name.
- The Grapes of Wrath, photograph (8" x 10"), 1940 (Box 19)
- Great American Cowboy, poster, 1973 (Box 2)
  Very scarce poster for Oscar-winning documentary about rodeo cowboys.
- Greed, photographs (8" x 10", set of 2), 1925 (Box 19)
  Rare photographs of Erich von Stroheim's 1925 film.
- Gun Law, poster, 1938 (Box 2)
  George O'Brien RKO western.
- Gun Smugglers, poster, 1949 (Box 2)
- Guns and Guitars, lobby card, 1936 (Box 2)
  An extremely early Republic film starring Gene Autry, who only got his first screen credit the year before!
- Hang 'Em High, poster, 1968 (Box 15 (Broadside))
  The first feature Clint Eastwood made after his completion of the famous trilogy of Italian films with Sergio Leone.
- The Hanging Tree, lobby card, 1959 (Box 2)
  Freudian-influenced western.
- Heart of the Rockies, title lobby cards, 1937 (Box 2)
  This was one of a series of B-westerns made by Republic featuring the "Three Mesquiteers" (Bob Livingston, Ray Corrigan, and Max Terhune).
- Heaven's Gate, poster, 1981 (Box 2)
  Michael Cimino's wildly ambitious film, which was reviled at the time of its release but which has slowly attained cult status if not full-fledged critical approval.
- High, Wide and Handsome, lobby cards, 1937 (Box 2)
  One issued by Paramount and two independently issued, and with different artwork.
- Highway Dragnet, lobby cards, 1954 (Box 2)
  Interesting example of low-budget film noir set in California.
- The Hired Gun, lobby card, 1957 (Box 2)
- His Brother's Ghost, poster, 1945 (Box 2)
  PRC western.
- His Fighting Blood, lobby card, 1935 (Box 2)
  Kermit Maynard western based on story by James Oliver Curwood.
- Hombre, poster, 1967 (Box 2)
- Hop-a-Long Cassidy, promotional flyer, 4to, 1 p., 1935 (Box 2)
  Extremely rare artifact from the first Hopalong Cassidy film, of which there were many subsequent sequels in this enormously popular series.
- Hot Lead, poster, 1951 (Box 2)
  Tim Holt RKO western.
- Hound-Dog Man, title lobby card, 1959 (Box 2)
  Early western by director Don Siegel.
- Houston Story, lobby card, 1955 (Box 2)
- Hud, poster, circa 1963-1967 (Box 16 (Broadside))
  Larry McMurtry's first screen credit, an Oscar-winning classic set in the modern west.
- Hula, photographs (8" x 10", set of 9), 1927 (Box 19)
  Clara Bow film, directed by Victor Fleming.
- I Died a Thousand Times, lobby card, 1955 (Box 2)
  Interesting remake of Raoul Walsh's High Sierra.
- Idaho, lobby card, 1943 (Box 2)
- Idaho Kid, lobby card, 1936 (Box 2)
  Rex Bell western.
- In Old Amarillo, poster, 1951 (Box 2)
  Roy Rogers Republic western.
- In Old Amarillo, lobby card, 1951 (Box 2)
- The James Brothers of Missouri, lobby cards, 1949 (Box 2)
- Jesse James, lobby card, 1939 (Box 2)
  This card is from the special deluxe set of color glossy cards, and it is a noteworthy scene of a bank holdup from this famous Henry King film.
- Jesse James, 1939 (Box 5)
- Jesse James, lobby card (14" x 8"), 1939 (Box 20 (Oversize))
- Johnny Concho, poster, 1956 (Box 2)
- Johnny Guitar, photograph (8" x 10"), 1954 (Box 2)
  Joan Crawford and Sterling Hayden from Nicholas Ray's truculent western allegory about McCarthyism
- Johnny Guitar, black and white photograph, circa 1954 (Box 20 (Oversize))
- Johnny Guitar (Mujar Pasional), Argentine poster (Box 8 (Roll))
- Junior Bonner, Poster, style B, 1972 (Box 17 (Broadside))
  Rare poster for Sam Peckinpah's film about rodeo life.
- Le Justicier Solitaire (The Lone Ranger), French pressbook, 4to, 4 pp., 1956 (Box 2)
  The Lone Ranger was featured for many years in a radio show, then in a popular televisison show, and this film featured the cast of the television show, most notably Clayton Moore in the title role.
- The Kansas Terrors, lobby cards, 1939 (Box 2)
  Republic western featuring the 3 Mesquiteers.
- The Kid from Texas, title lobby card and 5 lobby cards, 1939 (Box 2)
  MGM film set in the milieu of a traveling Wild West show.
- Last Command, poster, 1955 (Box 2)
  Republic film about the Alamo.
- Last of the Duanes, poster, circa 1941 (Box 2)
  Twentieth Century Fox western with George Montgomery.
- Last Pony Riders, poster, 1953 (Box 2)
- Law and Order, photographs (8" x 10"), 1953 (Box 2)
  Ronald Reagan western, which is of interest because, when he started his political career campaigning for governor of California in the 1960's, he was clearly running on a "law and order" platform.
- Law of the Barbary Coast, title lobby card, 1949 (Box 2)
- Law of the Texan, poster, on linen (Box 7 (Roll))
  A Buck Jones western gets here very interesting pulp artwork.
- Lawless Nineties, lobby card, 1936 (Box 2)
  A good representation of John Wayne's early journeyman career. From 1930, when he made his effective debut in Raoul Walsh's THE BIG TRAIL, until 1939, when John Ford's STAGECOACH revitalized both the film western and Wayne's career, he worked in numerous B-movies. This is an excellent example of one of those, a dramatic scene with close shot of Wayne grabbing a bandit with his left hand as he points his gun at him with his right hand.
- Lawless Riders, lobby card, 1935 (Box 2)
  Ken Maynard Columbia western.
- The Learning Tree, lobby cards (set of 8), 1969 (Box 20 (Oversize))
- The Learning Tree, black and white photographs (set of 10), 1969 (Box 20 (Oversize))
- The Leather Burners, lobby card, 1943 (Box 2)
  Hopalong Cassidy film.
- Lightnin' Bill Carson, title lobby card and 4 lobby cards, 1936 (Box 2)
  Tim McCoy western.
- The Littlest Outlaw, title lobby card, 1955 (Box 2)
- The Lone Ranger, lobby cards (11" x 14", set of 3), 1956 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  Clayton Moore film.
- Lone Star, lobby cards, 1951 (Box 2)
- The Long Goodbye, 11" x 14", set of 8), 1973 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  Adaptation of a Raymond Chandler novel, directed by Robert Altman.
- The Magnificent Seven, photograph (8" x 10"), 1960 (Box 19)
  Yul Brynner, Steve McQueen, Charles Bronson, and Eli Wallach film, directed by John Sturges.
- Man from Painted Post, lobby card, 1917 (Box 2)
  Extremely early and rare Douglas Fairbanks 8 x 10" lobby card from western. By the 1920's, Fairbanks had become a major film star, specialized in swashbuckling roles, and he did no more western films.
- Man With the Steel Whip, title lobby card, 6 lobby cards, 1954 (Box 2)
  Republic western serial.
- Marching On!, lobby card, circa 1943 (Box 20 (Oversize))
- Mark of Zorro, poster, circa 1958 (Box 2)
  Classic Rouben Mamoulian 1940 film, with Tyrone Power as Zorro.
- Mildred Pierce, photograph (8" x 10"), circa 1945-1956 (Box 2)
  Joan Crawford and Zachary Scott in adaptation of James Cain novel---a classic film noir with a strong feeling for southern California in the 1930's.
- Moon Over Las Vegas, title lobby card, 1944 (Box 3)
- My Darling Clementine, lobby card (8" x 10"), 1946 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  John Ford directed film, staring Victor Mature and Linda Darnell.
- My Friend Flicka, title lobby card and one lobby card, 1943 (Box 3)
- My Own Pal, lobby card, 1926 (Box 3)
  Tom Mix silent western.
- Nevada City, lobby card, 1941 (Box 3)
- Night Stage to Galveston, lobby card, 1952 (Box 3)
- No Man's Gold, lobby card, 1926 (Box 3)
- North of the Great Divide, lobby card, 1950 (Box 3)
- North to Alaska, pressbook, folio, 8 pp. and additional advertising, folio, 4 pp., 1960 (Box 5)
- Northwest Outpost, lobby card, 1947 (Box 3)
  Allan Dwan film.
- Of Mice and Men, lobby card (11" x 14"), 1939 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  Lewis Milestone directed film, based on the novel by John Steinbeck. Stars Lon Chaney Jr. and Burgess Meredith.
- Oklahoma Territory, poster, 1960 (Box 3)
- O'Malley of the Mounted, 1936 (Box 3)
- One Eyed Jacks, poster, 1961 (Box 3)
  The only film directed by Marlon Brando, and a rather legendary account of betrayal and retribution. Originally, Stanley Kubrick was directed, but Brando fired him in mid-project and took over the helming of this now classic work.
- One-Eyed Jacks, lobby cards, 1961 (Box 3)
- Oregon Trail, lobby card, 1939 (Box 3)
  From Chapter 3 of a Universal serial.
- The Outlaw, lobby card (11" x 14"), 1941 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  Notorious Howard Hughes western, reputedly with extensive sequences shot by an uncredited Howard Hawks.
- The Outlaw, photograph (8" x 10"), 1941 (Box 19)
- The Outlaw, trade ad, 2 pp., 1941 (Box 3)
- The Outlaw Deputy, lobby cards, 1935 (Box 3)
- The Outlaw Is Coming, lobby card, 1965 (Box 3)
- Outlaw Treasure, poster, 1955 (Box 3)
- Outlawed, lobby card, 1929 (Box 3)
- Outlaws of Stampede Pass, lobby card, 1943 (Box 3)
  Johnny Mack Brown and Raymond Hatton western.
- Outlaw's Son, poster, 1957 (Box 3)
- Pack Train, lobby train, 1953 (Box 3)
- Partners of the Trail, lobby card, 1931 (Box 3)
  Early talking Monogram western with Tom Tyler.
- Pat Garrett and Billy the Kid, poster on linen, 1973 (Box 3)
  Very rare Columbia Records poster for Bob Dylan soundtrack. Heartbreaking revisionist western, recently restored, with Kris Kristofferson and James Coburn. Elaborate photomontage has five images of Bob Dylan and at least four of Sam Peckinpah.
- Pat Garrett and Billy the Kid, circa 1973 (Box 9 (Roll))
- The Patriot, lobby card (11" x 14"), 1916 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  Directed by, and starring, William S. Hart.
- Per Qualche Dollaro in più (For a Few Dollars More), Italian poster on linen. (Box 10 (Roll))
  The original Italian poster for this classic Italian Sergio Leone western, with iconic artwork of Clint Eastwood
- The Plainsman, lobby card, 1937 (Box 3)
  Cecil B. DeMille film, in which Gary Cooper played Wild Bill Hickok and Jean Arthur, Calamity Jane.
- The Plainsman, photograph (8" x 10"), 1946 (Box 3)
- The Postman Always Rings Twice, lobby card (11" x 14"), 1945 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  Tay Garnett directed film, adapted from the James M. Cain novel, starring Lana Turner.
- Psycho, lobby card (11" x 14"), 1960 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  Alfred Hitchcock directed film, based on the novel by Robert Bloch, starring Anthony Perkins and Janet Leigh.
- Pursued, lobby cards (set of 8), 1947 (Box 3)
  Raoul Walsh's western with Robert Mitchum is an extraordinarily important film---almost certainly the first western to incorporate visual and thematic elements of film noir, and also one of the earliest western films to make use of Freudian psychology in its rather twisted flashback-ridden plot.
- Queen of the Yukon, poster, 1940 (Box 3)
  Western adventure film, adapted from Jack London.
- Rawhide, lobby card, 1956 (Box 3)
- The Rawhide Trail, poster, 1958 (Box 3)
- Rebel Without a Cause, photographs (8" x 10", set of 12), 1955 (Box 19)
  James Dean film, directed by Nicholas Ray.
- Reckless Ranger, lobby card, 1937 (Box 3)
  Bob Allen in Columbia film.
- Red River, photograph (8" x 10"), 1948 (Box 3)
  Portrait of John Wayne and Montgomery Clift from Howard Hawks epic western classic. This photo has typed studio text on back, and was obviously used for publication at the time of the film's original release.
- Revenge Rider, poster on linen (Box 11 (Roll))
  Artwork for Tim McCoy B-western for Columbia.
- Ride the High Country, color stills (8" x 10", set of 12), 1962 (Box 3)
  Sam Peckinpah's elegiac western starred two aging icons of the genre, Randolph Scott and Joel McCrea, in his second feature and his first masterpiece.
- Ridin' Down the Canyon, lobby card, 1942 (Box 3)
- Ridin' the Wind, lobby card, 1925 (Box 3)
- The Riding Avenger, 1936 (Box 3)
- Riding High, lobby card, 1943 (Box 3)
- Riding Shotgun, pressbook, folio, 8 pp., 1956 (Box 3)